Becca King

TITLE

Full-Stack Web Developer with Journalism Experience

CONTACT

216-570-0627 rebecca.lynne.king@gmail.com Cleveland, OH 44102

WEBSITE

rebeccaking.info

SKILLS

HTML CSS CSS Preprocessors (i.e. Less) JavaScript jQuery React (training only) Git version control SQL (Microsoft SQL Server), Relational Databases Progress OpenEdge (back-end language) WordPress, including PHP for WordPress Journalism and Nonfiction Writing Excel, Google Sheets Google Tag Manager and Google Analytics **API Integration**

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

I am a full-stack web developer with a background in journalism, and I am passionate about creating engaging online experiences for diverse audiences. I've worked closely with news editors, information technologists, designers, and e-commerce experts to fulfill company goals and advance digital products.

EXPERIENCE

Amerimark Direct, LLC, Web Developer

Middleburg Heights, OH - Nov 2020 - Current

- Primary front-end specialist on a team of web developers.
- Developed front and back end solutions based on design specifications and information technology needs.
- Completed training in React, SQL, and web accessibility.

We Write Blog Posts, Ghostwriter

Jul 2020 - Current

- Completed exhaustive research on diverse topics to create accurate and engaging stories.
- Adapted tone and wording choice to successfully connect with different target audiences.
- Reviewed work in detail to correct factual errors and grammatical problems.

North Coast Media, Web Developer

Cleveland, OH - Jan 2020 - Jul 2020

- Full stack development of websites based on a WordPress CMS.
- Technologies used include HTML, CSS, JavaScript, jQuery, Git, WordPress, PHP, SQL, Google Tag Manager.
- Developed websites to work properly across multiple browsers, including those created by Microsoft, Google, and Mozilla.

AWS (personal projects using Route 53, Amplify)

EDUCATION

General Assembly
Software Engineering
Certificate program in
full-stack web development.
Created web applications using
JavaScript, jQuery, PHP,
Angular, React, SQL, MongoDb,
HTML, CSS, Git version control.

Miami University
Bachelor of Science
Kinesiology
Environmental Science
University Honors Program

E.W. Scripps School of
Journalism, Ohio University
Master of Science
Journalism
Athens, Ohio
Completed two years of
coursework in digital media,
communication law, and media
economics before leaving out
of medical necessity.

Freelance, Magazine Writer

Jan 2020 - Mar 2020

- Wrote articles for Teen Vogue and LGBTQ Nation.
- Used appropriate tone and diction to compose engaging content for audiences of various ages.
- Maintained updated understanding of writing industry and genre trends to strengthen writing success and marketability.

Ohio University, Graduate Assistant in Journalism

Athens, OH - Aug 2017 - May 2019

- Studied the fundamentals of digital journalism, communication law, and media economics to become a well-rounded professional in the journalism field.
- Worked as a research assistant in journalism for varied university departments.

Freelance, News Writer

Athens, Ohio - Sep 2017 - Jun 2018

- Generated original story ideas, developed fresh perspectives, and oversaw story development from inception to completion.
- Wrote exciting, captivating, and authentic pieces to engage audience members.

Americorps - La Puente Shelter, Community Educator and Volunteer Coordinator

Alamosa, CO - Aug 2016 - Jan 2017

- Created news and radio press releases on behalf of a rural homeless shelter.
- Built relationships with the local community and visiting volunteers.
- Gathered and edited stories for and designed a 32-page storybook on behalf of the organization. Used Indesign and Adobe Photoshop under the guidance of a professional graphic designer.